Finding Aid for Carl Eugen Guthe Papers
Bentley Historical Library
- Clippings, 1916-1965
  Clippings, 1916-1965, (.25 linear feet) comprises three folders of newspaper clippings about Guthe and his family, and are particularly strong in documenting Guthe's travels throughout the U.S. and Canada surveying museums after his retirement.
  - Grace Guthe (Box 7)
  - Guthe Sons (Box 7)
  - Early Career (pre-1943) (Box 7)
  - Later Career (post-1943) (Box 7)
  - U. S. Museums Tour and Study (Box 7)
  - Canadian Museums Tour and Study (Box 7)
- Other, 1916-1960
  Other, 1916-1960, (.25 linear feet) includes a small number of documents that do not fit into any of the other categories. They include memorabilia from Guthe's time at Harvard (1916-1917), a roster of the Ann Arbor High School Class of 1910 with notes on whereabouts as of 1960, and forms filled out during anthropometrical examinations of Dr. and Mrs. Guthe at Harvard.
  - Harvard Memorabilia, 1916-1917 (Box 7)
  - Notes from a Course Taught by Guthe, 1935 (Box 7)
  - Exam forms from Harvard Anthropometry, 1937 (Box 7)
  - Ann Arbor High School Class of 1910 Roster with Notes, 1960 (Box 7)
  - Guthe Family Genealogy (Box 7)
- Photographs, 1911-1971
  Photographs, 1911-1971, (.75 linear feet) comprises several hundred small (mostly 2-1/2"x3" and 3"x5" size) prints, mostly from Guthe's field work in the U.S. Southwest, Central America and the Philippines. These images show Guthe and his colleagues engaged in archaeological excavations, and document the excavation sites and artifacts. This series also includes a small number of photographs of the Guthe Family, including an oversize photograph from 1911. Additional photographs can be found in the 1944 accession photographs series.
  - U. S. Southwest Expeditions, 1916-1917; 1921
    - Pecos and Rowe (Box 7)
    - New Mexico (Box 7)
    - "Duplicates or Near Duplicates" (Box 7)
    - "Unorganized" (Box 7)
  - Central America Expedition, 1920-1922
    - 1920-1922, 3 folders (Box 7)
    - "Key Prints of Films Sent to Jessups" (Box 7)
    - "Final Discards in the Making up of Final Album of Combined Trips. Many Good Prints in this Set" (Box 7)
    - "General Discards and Duplicates" (Box 7)
    - "Duplicates and Album Rejects. Many Good Prints in this Bunch." (Box 7)
    - "Key Prints of Films on Hand of Which no Good Prints Have Been Made.", 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Philippines Expedition, 1922-1925
    - Excavations, pottery, etc., 2 folders (Box 7)
    - Personal Guthe Family Photographs (Box 7)
    - Negatives Numbers 700-796 (Box 7)
  - Personal
    - Guthe Family (oversize), 1911 (Box 7)
    - Photographs of Guthe (Box 7)
    - Philippines, Starkey (?) B.H., Van Rippen (South Africa), Detroit (Box 7)
    - "Duplicates and Enlargements" (Box 7)
    - Miscellaneous and Post Cards (Box 7)
    - Miscellaneous 8 x 10 photographs, 1944-1971 (Box 7)
  - Archaeological excavations in Kentucky and Ohio, 1927 (Box 3)